molloy.edu 2010-06-24

# Molloy College

| 

**Introduction**   
Thank you for visiting the Molloy College Web site. This Web site is designed to make it easier and more efficient for individuals and businesses to interact with Molloy College. The College recognizes that it is critical for all audiences to be confident their privacy is protected when they visit Molloy's Web site. 

Molloy College employs various measures to protect the security of its computing resources and of users’ accounts.  Users should be aware, however, that Molloy College cannot guarantee such security.  Users should therefore establish appropriate access restrictions for their accounts, guarding passwords and changing them regularly.

Users should also be aware that use of Molloy College’s computing resources is not completely private.  While Molloy College does not routinely monitor individual usage of its computing resources, the normal operation and maintenance of its computing resources require the backup and caching of data and communications, the logging of activity, the monitoring of usage patterns, and other such activities that are necessary for the rendition of service.  Molloy College may specifically monitor the activity and accounts of individual users of its computing resources, including individual login sessions and communications, without notice, when (a) the user has voluntarily made them accessible to the public, as by posting to Usenet or a web page; (b) it reasonably appears necessary to do so to protect the integrity, security or functionality of Molloy College or other computing resources or to protect Molloy College from liability; (c) there is reasonable cause to believe that the user has violated, or is violating, this policy; (d) an account appears to be engaged in unusual or unusually excessive activity, as indicated by the monitoring of general activity and usage patterns; or (e) it is otherwise required or permitted by law.  Any such individual monitoring, other than that specified in (a), required by law, or necessary to respond to perceived emergency situations, must be authorized in advance by Molloy College’s Web Developer.

Molloy College, in its discretion, may disclose the results of any such general or individual monitoring, including the contents and records of individual communications, to appropriate College personnel or law enforcement agencies and may use those results in appropriate College disciplinary proceedings.

Consistent with the provisions of New York's Internet Security and Privacy Act, Freedom of Information Law and Personal Privacy Protection Law, and applicable federal laws, this policy describes Molloy's privacy practices regarding information collected from users of this Web site. This policy describes what information is collected and how that information is used. Because this privacy policy applies only to this Web site, you should examine the privacy policy of any Web site, including other educational Web sites, that you access while using this Web site. When you link from Molloy's Web site, please refer to the linked site's own privacy policy before you volunteer any personal information. 

For purposes of this policy, "personal information" means any information concerning a person that, because of name, number, symbol, mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that person. 

**Information Collected Automatically When You Visit This Web Site**  
When you visit this Web site, Molloy automatically collects and stores the following non-personal information about your visit: 

|   
(i)  | 

The Internet Protocol Address and domain name used, but not the e-mail address. The Internet Protocol Address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer;  
  
---|---  
  
(ii)

| 

The type of browser and operating system you used;  
  
(iii) 

| 

The date and time you visited this site;  
  
(iv)

| 

The Web pages or services you accessed at this site;  
  
(v)

| 

The Web site you visited before coming to this site;  
  
(vi)

| 

The Web site you visit as you leave this site;   
  
(vii)

| 

If you downloaded a file, the file that was downloaded; and  
  
(viii)     

| 

Any server error messages you may receive while using our site.  
  
The information that is collected automatically is used to improve this Web site's content and to help Molloy understand how users are interacting with the Web site. This information is collected for statistical analysis, to determine what information is of most and least interest to our users, and to make it easier to use the material on the Web site. The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and Molloy does not sell or disclose this information for any reason.   
**  
Cookies**   
Cookies are simple text files stored on your Web browser to distinguish among users of this Web site. The use of cookies is a standard practice among Internet Web sites. To better serve you, we use "session cookies" to enhance or customize your visit to this Web site. Session cookies can be created automatically on the device you use to access Molloy's Web site. These session cookies do not contain personal information and do not compromise your privacy or security. We may use the cookie feature to store a randomly generated identifying tag on the device you use to access this Web site. A session cookie is erased during operation of your browser or when your browser is closed.   
The software and hardware you use to access Molloy's Web site allows you to refuse new cookies or delete existing cookies. Refusing or deleting these cookies may limit your ability to take advantage of some features of this Web site. 

**Information and Choice**   
As noted below, Molloy does not collect any personal information about you during your visit to this Web site unless you voluntarily provide that information by sending an e-mail or conducting an online transaction. If you choose not to participate in these activities, your ability to receive specific services or products through this Web site may be limited, but it will not prevent you from requesting some of our services by other means, nor will it affect your ability to take advantage of other features of the Web site, including browsing or downloading publicly available information. 

**The New York State Internet Security and Privacy Act**   
The collection of information through this Web site and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the state's Internet Security and Privacy Act. Molloy will collect or disclose personal information through this Web site only if you have consented to the collection or disclosure of personal information. By using the Molloy Web Site, you give Molloy permission to collect, use and disclose the information you voluntarily provide.   
However, Molloy may collect or disclose personal information without user consent if the collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform the statutory duties of Molloy, or necessary for Molloy to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation; (2) made pursuant to a court order or by law; (3) for the purpose of validating the identity of the user; or (4) of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person.   
Molloy may disclose personal information to federal or state law enforcement authorities, or use this personal information to enforce Molloy's rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to Molloy's information technology assets. 

**Information Collected When You E-mail This Web Site**   
During your visit to this Web site you may send an e-mail to Molloy. Your e-mail address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats included in the message. Your e-mail address and the information included in your message will be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this Web site, or to forward your message to another state agency for appropriate action. Your e-mail address is not collected for commercial purposes and Molloy does not sell or disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes. 

**Information Collected When You Make A Credit Card Bill Payment**   
If you visit this Web site to make a credit card payment on your outstanding balance, Molloy will provide a data entry screen that transmits your credit card information to the Web site of VeriSign, a credit card service provider, to process the transaction. Molloy will not receive any of your non-public, personal information. The credit card service provider "VeriSign" will forward to Molloy only that information necessary for Molloy to properly credit the payment to your account. For more information about VeriSign's treatment of your non-public personal information, see the Privacy and other policies displayed on VeriSign's Web site. 

**Information Utilized When You Use TAP on the Web**  
Molloy's TAP on the Web may be accessed via the Federal FAFSA (Free Application for Federal Student Aid) on the Web or by going to the URL provided by the Molloy College Financial Aid Department on the e-mail or postcard mailed to you. Before you begin the TAP on the Web process, your identity will be authenticated based upon the non-public personal information you provide such as name, Social Security Number, date of birth, etc. The authentication process identifies who you are, provides you with a Molloy USER ID and PIN, and serves to help safeguard your non-public personal information. 

If you enter Molloy's TAP on the Web via the Federal FAFSA, the information including non-public personal information, volunteered by you during the FAFSA process is pre-filled on your TAP on the Web application. This information includes your name, Social Security Number, income, marital status, et al. and that of your spouse and your parent(s). Non- public personal information you provide during the TAP on the Web process is used to determine your eligibility and award amounts under the TAP program, and to verify data. Access to this information is limited to Molloy staff that require access to perform their official duties and to staff with security access, as initiated by a designated school official.  
Most of this personal information is retained indefinitely by Molloy as part of your academic record.   Your name, date of birth, and Social Security Number, however, are retained in perpetuity.

Failure to provide FAFSA with all information necessary to process your TAP on the Web application will result in an inability to process your TAP application. You may apply for TAP via a paper TAP application [available at the Molloy College Financial Aid office].

**Information Collected When You Register for Workshops or Events on This Web Site**   
If, during your visit to this Web site, you register for a workshop or an event, the information, including personal information, volunteered by you is used by Molloy to enroll you in the workshop or event, and to provide you with your requested information. Access to this information is limited to Molloy staff who require access to perform their official duties. This information will not be collected for commercial purposes and Molloy is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes. 

**Federally Required Disclosures:**   
Nonpublic personal information means personal information about you, which identifies you and that is not available from public sources. 

  1. We collect nonpublic personal information about you from the following sources:
    * Information we receive from you on loan, grant and scholarship applications and promissory notes; 
    * Information you provide us voluntarily during any interaction, including e-mail; 
    * Information about your transactions with us or others with respect to your student loan (from parties such as your lenders and the U.S. Department of Education and their agents); 
    * Information about your New York State student financial aid (from agencies such as the NYS Education Department, the NYS Department of Taxation and Finance and the NYS Department of Motor Vehicles); 
    * Information received from schools you attend or formerly attended, or to which you have applied for admission; and 
    * Information received from credit reporting agencies. 

  2. We do not disclose any nonpublic personal information about you to anyone except as permitted or required by law (for example, we share such information with our contractors and agents, and with schools, lenders and the U.S. Department of Education, as needed, to administer your loan in conformance with the law).
  3. We restrict access to nonpublic information about you to our employees who need to know the information. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards in compliance with federal regulations to safeguard your nonpublic personal information.
  4. Molloy does not knowingly collect personal information from children or create profiles of children through this Web site. Users are cautioned, however, that the collection of personal information submitted in an e-mail will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or state law, be subject to public access. Molloy strongly encourages parents and teachers to be involved in children's Internet activities and to provide guidance whenever children are asked to provide personal information online. 

**Disclaimer**   
The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided through this Web site. 

**Contact Information**  
For questions regarding this Internet privacy policy, please contact:   
Molloy College   
Web Developer  
P.O. Box 5002   
1000 Hempstead Ave.   
Rockville Centre, NY 11570
